A. Howry Espenshade papers, 1911-1947 00279
Eberly Family Special Collections Library
A. Howry Espenshade papers
1911-1947
Eberly Family Special Collections Library
00279
2 Cubic feet
A. Howry Espenshade came to Pennsylvania State College in 1898 as an instructor of rhetoric and elocution. He was appointed professor in 1917, served as registrar from 1909 to 1923, and retired in 1937 with emeritus rank.
This collection of papers of Penn State rhetoric professor A. Howry Espenshade includes his correspondence, manuscripts, exams and laboratory worksheets, papapers and reviews.
Biographical or Historical Note
A. Howry Espenshade joined the faculty of the Pennsylvania State College in 1898 as an instructor of rhetoric and elocution. In 1901, he was promoted to assistant professor of English and rhetoric and became an associate professor in 1906. In 1909, Espenshade was named the first registrar of the College and was appointed professor of rhetoric in 1917. He resigned his post as registrar in 1923 to return to fulltime teaching. In 1928, he was named head of the Department of English Composition and retired in 1937 with emeritus rank.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
- Poem Scroll, 1918 (Box 1)
- Pennsylvania County Names, Definitions and History, Undated (Box 1)
- Words Derived from the American Indian Languages, Undated (Box 2)
- Old Main Items List, 1929 (Box 3)
- Registrar Promotion, 1912-1947 (Box 3)
- Related Data, 1908-1920 (Box 3)
- Papers and Correspondence, 1915-1918 (Box 3)
- Correspondence, 1924-1925 (Box 3)
- Rejected Parts Manuscript, Undated (Box 3)
- Origin of County Names, 1911-1916 (Box 3)
- Evangelical Press, 1924-1925 (Box 3)
- Book Rough Draft, 1925 (Box 3)
- Returned Manuscript, Undated (Box 3)
- Pond Scum Book, 1914 (Box 3)
- Horticulture 2 Practicum, 1917 (Box 3)
- Final Exam, 1913-1914 (Box 3)
- Laboratory Worksheets, Undated (Box 3)
- Name Book Chapters I - XXV, Undated (Box 3)
- Manuscript Chapters VII, VIII, X, XVI, 1922 (Box 3)
- Articles and Letters, 1925 (Box 3)
- Data, Undated (Box 3)
- Reviews and Testimonials, 1925 (Box 3)
- Advanced Order Letters, 1925 (Box 3)
- Correspondence and Data, 1916-1925 (Box 3)